<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: raspberry pi | Encoded Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://RadioactiveMouse.github.com/blog/categories/raspberry-pi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://RadioactiveMouse.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-14T15:16:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://RadioactiveMouse.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom Townsend]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Setup]]></title>
    <link href="http://RadioactiveMouse.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/raspberry-pi-setup/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T14:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://RadioactiveMouse.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/raspberry-pi-setup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Basic Tools and settings</h2>

<p>I should probably start by mentioning that I use the Pi headless, connected via the very good Edimax wifi adapter.</p>

<p>Below is a list of the various applications that I have installed via Apt:</p>

<ul>
<li>Screen (essential for any compilation as described further down the post</li>
<li>Erlang (necessary for building Riak)</li>
<li>Git (essential version control software that is also used to get Riak)</li>
<li>Mecurial (another version control tool for retrieving Go)</li>
<li>Vim (text editor with optional syntax highlighting)</li>
</ul>


<p>I also compile various tools necessary to any development. This where screen (or tmux) work really well. By utilising Screen I can run several development tasks in concert with eachother. This means I can compile both Riak and Go at the same time making it much more convenient. The: programs are as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>Riak (cloned &amp; installed from Github repo, approx 90mins)</li>
<li>Go (programming language grabbed by mecurial and built as per http://dave.cheney.net/2012/09/25/installing-go-on-the-raspberry-pi , approx 90mins)</li>
<li>Node JS (Built from source in usual way, approx 100mins)</li>
</ul>


<p>I also create .screenrc and .vimrc files early on in order to configure the behaviour of this software.</p>

<p>Overall there aren't too many other programs needed to get started using the Raspberry Pi as a tiny development server. My current setup is based around my use of Panic's excellent Prompt SSH client on the iPad. I intend to use this setup up to create and run Go programs including the Riak library which is the focus of my dissertation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
